洛杉磯西元2029年
那些機器從核子戰火中崛起
它們滅絕人類的戰爭肆虐數十年
但最後的一場仗不會在未來掀起
它會發生在這裡  就是現在
就在今晚
片名: 終結者
洛杉磯1984年淩晨1點52分
怎麼了?  他媽的
What the hell? Goddamn son-of-a-bitch
什麼事?
What the hell?
輪到我了
Hey, my turn.
來吧
come on
這個人在搞什麼鬼?
Hey, what's wrong with this picture?
夜色很好  適宜散步?
Nice night for a walk?
夜色很好  適宜散步
Nice night for a walk.
明天是洗衣日  沒乾淨衣服穿  是嗎?
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean, right?
對  沒乾淨衣服
Nothing clean. Right.
這個傢伙一定是喝醉了
I think this guy's a couple of cans short of a six-pack.
你的衣服  馬上給我
Your clothes, give them to me.
-快啊  -去你的  混蛋
-Now.  -Fuck you, asshole.
嘿  甜心  怎麼樣?
Hey, sugar, how about it?
我不必忍受那個的
I don't have to put up with that bullshit, man.
她老是纏著我
She's always after me.
兄弟  你有沒有見到一道強光?
Hey, buddy, did you just see a real bright light?
-看到那傢伙嗎?  -別動
-See that guy?  -Hold it right there.
-他在逃跑  -別動  去吧
-He's rabbiting.  -Hey! I said hold it! Go.
那個混蛋搶了我的褲子
That son-of-a-bitch took my pants.
-今天是什麼日子?  日期  -5月12號
-What day is it? The date.  -12th May.
-星期四  -什麼年份?
-Thursday.  -What year?
他搶了我的槍  快追
He's got my gun. Let's go.
薩拉·康納
大塊頭  替我守著它
Guard it for me, Big Buns.
你好  我遲到了
Hi. I'm late.
我也是
So am I.
薩拉·康納
-開工了  -我也是
-I'm in it.  -So am I.
-麻煩你拿咖啡給我  好嗎?  -好的
-Honey, can I have that coffee now?  -Yes, sir.
-牛排是誰的?  -我叫了烤牛肉
-OK. Who gets the burly-beef?  -I ordered barbecued.
我叫的  但我沒有叫薯條
That's mine, but I didn't order fries.
-我叫的是辣牛肉  -誰點牛排?
-Mine's the chilli beef deluxe. -Who gets the burly-beef?
-我們想點菜  -好的
-We're ready to order now.  -Yes, ma'am.
對不起
I'm so sorry.
這不是真皮吧?
This isn't real leather, is it?
孩子  做得好  我該把小費給你
Nice going, kid. I ought to give you the tip.
要這樣想  一百年後誰會在乎?
Look at it this way. In 100 years, who's gonna care?
那支12口徑自動步槍
The 12-gauge auto-loader.
義大利製造  可以選手動或自動
That's ltalian. You can go pump or auto.
點45口徑滑動式配鐳射瞄準器
The 45 long slide with laser sighting.
全新的  我們剛收到的  是支好槍
These are new. We just got them in. That's a good gun.
鐳射光亮起時
The beam comes on,
你把紅點對準目標就行
you put the red dot where you want the bullet to go.
百發百中
You can't miss.
-還有什麼需要?  -40瓦的同步等離子步槍
-Anything else? -Plasma rifle in the 40-watt range.
就是你看到的了
Hey, just what you see, pal.
那支烏茲型九毫米
The Uzi nine millimetre.
你很熟識槍械
You know your weapons, buddy.
任何一支都適合家居防衛
Any one of these is ideal for home defence.
那麼  要哪一支呢?
So which will it be?
-全部  -今天可以提早關門了
-All.  -I may close early today.
手槍要等15日  但步槍現在就能拿走了
It's a 15-day wait on the handguns, but the rifles you can take now.
-你不能這樣做  -錯
-You can't do that.  -Wrong.
你好  寶貝  是我
Hi, baby. Yeah, yeah, it's me.
我要你來接我  我的電單車壞了
Listen, I need you to come pick me up. My bike just broke down.
我不管你在做什麼  快來接我  什麼...
I don't care what you're doing. Come and get me. What the...?
莫特?
Matt!
你的態度很有問題
Hey, man, you got a serious attitude problem.
莫特  你在哪裡?
Matt! where are you
別這樣  你在幹什麼?
come on  what are you doing?
薩拉·康納...
-薩拉·康納?  -是的
-Sarah Connor?  -Yes?
我在休息  卡拉代替我
I'm on my break, Chuck. Carla's got my station.
薩拉  過來  這算是跟你有關的
Sarah, come here. It's about you. I mean, sort of.
-不可思議  你不會相信的  -你會喜歡這個的
-Incredible.You're not gonna believe this.  -You're going to love this.
-什麼?  -有幾個目擊證人指出
-What?  -compiled from several witnesses.
又一位薩拉·康納  35歲  有兩名子女
Once again, Sarah Connor, 35, mother of two,
今天下午在家裡中槍身亡
brutally shot to death this afternoon.
你死了
You're dead, honey.
如果你喜歡音響
if you're into sound,
最佳的音響 就是鮑博身歷聲
for the greatest sound around, come to Bob's Stereo at 2500 Sepulveda.
我們有低音炮 高頻炮 數碼揚聲器和鐳射唱片
We've got woofers, tweeters, the newest in audio and compact discs.
還有圖表等化器和音響平衡器
We've got graphic equalisers and sound balancers that
對不起
Sorry.
你好
Hello?
首先  我會一個個的解開你的衫鈕
First I'm gonna rip the buttons off your blouse one by one,
然後用舌頭 從你的頭舔到你赤裸的乳房
then run my tongue down your neck to your bare, gleaming breasts.
然後慢慢地  逐英寸地脫掉你的牛仔褲
And then slowly...slowly pull your jeans off inch by inch.
金珍  是馬特
Ginger, it's Matt.
然後舔你的肚皮...再往下麵去
And lick your belly in circles further and further down,
然後用牙齒...脫掉你的內褲
and then pull your panties off with my teeth.
你是誰?
Who is this?
天啊  薩拉?
God. Sarah?
我的天  對不起
Jesus. I'm sorry.
我以為你是...我想找金珍
I thought you were...Can I talk to Ginger?
好的
Sure.
是那個變態鬼
It's the creep.
你好
Hello?
首先  我會一個個解開你的衫鈕
First I'll rip the buttons off your blouse one by one...
你們這群混蛋  等著我對付你們  放手
You fucking pigs. Wait till I get my hands on you. Get off me.
坐下
sit down
艾特
Ed.
-你有什麼?  -女死者
-What have you got?  -Dead girl.
-我看得到  -薩拉·康納  秘書  35歲
-I can see that.  -Sarah Ann Connor, secretary, 35.
在不足十英尺內身中六槍  大口徑武器
Shot six times at less than 10 feet. Large calibre weapon.
我看得清楚
You know, these work.
-這是什麼?  -第二名女死者
-What's this?  -Dead girl two.
今天下午山谷區分區送過來的
Sent over from the Valley division this afternoon.
我肯定這些命案是有動機的
Are you sure there's a point to all of this?
看看死者的名字
Look at the name, Ed.
薩拉·路易士·康納...有沒有弄錯?
Sarah Louise Connor. Is this right?
你說笑吧
You're kidding.
報紙會大做文章的
The press is gonna be short-stroking it.
-一個有特定模式的兇手  -我討厭古怪的案件
-A one-day pattern killer.  -I hate the weird ones.
所以...
So...
比凡人得到的更好
Better than mortal man deserves.
-你有見過寶斯利嗎?  -最近沒有
-Ginger, have you seen Pugsley?  -Not lately.
-你聽了口信沒有?  -我以為你聽了
-Did you check messages?  -I thought you did.
-薩拉  是媽  -原來你在這裡
-Hi, Sarah, this is your mom...  -There you are, young man.
你想想你媽吧
You mind your mother.
再見
Bye
你好  薩拉  莫仕庭  有突發事件
Hi, Sarah. Stan Morsky. Something's come up.
我不能應約了  我不能丟下不理的
Looks like I won't be able to make it tonight. Just can't get out of it.
對不起  我會給你賠罪的
I'm really sorry. I'll make it up to you.
改天找你吧  對不起  再見
Call you in a day or so. Bye.
那個混蛋  有輛保時捷又怎樣
That bum. So what if he has a Porsche?
他不能這樣對你的  這可是週五晚上
He can't treat you like this. It's Friday night, for Christ's sake.
我沒事的
I'll live.
我會打爆他的膝蓋
I'll break his kneecaps.
寶斯利仍然愛我  是嗎?
Well, Pugsley still loves me. Don't you, baby?
天  真噁心
God. It's disgusting.
-我去看電影  -你和馬特玩得開心點
-I'm gonna go to a movie, kiddo.  -Have a good time.
-我們會的  你也是  -好的
-We will. You, too.  -OK.
該死  馬特
Damn it, Matt.
該死
Shit.
這些命案 是依電話簿裡的次序發生的?
These killings occurred in the order of their listings in the phone book.
-我可以說什麼?  無可奉告  -但是...
-What can I tell you? No comment. -But, Lieutenant...
那杯咖啡早就涼了
That coffee's two hours cold.
我還用它弄熄香煙
I put a cigarette out in it.
-找到下一名女子了嗎?  -沒  只有電話留言
-Did you reach the next girl yet? -No. I got her answering machine.
-派組人去  -已經派了  還沒回音
-Send a unit.  -I sent a unit. There's no answer.
-那個經理還沒回家  -打電話給她
-The apartment manager's not in.  -Call her.
-剛打了  -再打
-I just called her.  -Call her again.
給我一支香煙
Give me a cigarette.
你好  捉弄到你了  你在跟留言機談話
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但別害羞  留言機也需要愛的  跟它談談吧
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too, so talk to it...
金珍  是我啦...
and Ginger, that's me,
或者薩拉會回復你的  等候嗶嗶聲啦
or Sarah will get back to you. Wait for the beep.
又是一樣
Same shit.
我現在聽到了 就叫他"電話簿殺手"吧
I can hear it now. He's gonna be called the goddamn Phone Book Killer.
我討厭這些觸目案件  特別是變態的案件
I hate these press cases. Especially the weird press cases.
-你去哪裡?  -發表聲明
-Where are you going?  -To make a statement.
叫這班走狗替我們工作
Maybe make these jackals work for us.
若我11點前能上電視  或許她會找我們的
If I can get on the tube by eleven o'clock, maybe she'll call us.
怎樣?  我的樣子怎樣?
Well, how do I look?
-很難看  老總  -不錯
-Like shit, boss.  -Your mama.
剛收到消息  警方已經宣佈了
This just in. Police have announced the name of the victim
今天發生的命案的  第二名死者的姓名
in the second of two murders which took place today.
奇怪的是  兩名死者都是同名同姓
Incredibly, the names of the two victims are virtually identical.
兩小時前  35歲的薩拉·康納...被發現死在寓所裡
Two hours ago, 35-year-old Sarah Ann Connor was pronounced dead...
-轉檯吧  -薩拉·路易士...
-Can we change this?  -Sarah Louise...
別碰它
Don't touch it.
在她家中被殺
murdered earlier today in her home.
警方拒絕猜測
Police are refusing to speculate
兩宗案件的類同之處
on the similarity between the shooting deaths
現在仍未發現兩者之間有何關連
and no other connection between the two victims has been established yet.
我們會隨時為大家報導最新消息
We'll have more on this late-breaking story as it comes in.
薩拉·康納...
黑科技酒吧
-有電話嗎?  -在裡面
-Hey, you got a phone?  -It's in the back.
四元五角
Hey. Four-fifty.
你已接通洛杉磯警局緊急熱線
You have reached the Los Angeles Police emergency number.
所有線路正忙
All lines are busy.
如需警車支援  請稍候
If you need a police car sent out to you, stay on the line.
走開  我會拿你來制皮帶
Go on. I'm gonna make a belt out of you.
別逼我打你
Don't make me bust you up, man.
你好  捉弄到你了  你在跟留言機談話
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但別害羞  留言機也需要愛的
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too.
跟它談談吧...金珍 是我啦 或者薩拉會回復你的
So talk to it and Ginger, that's me, or Sarah will get back to you.
等候嗶嗶聲啦
Wait for the beep.
金珍  我是薩拉  快接聽
Ginger. This is Sarah. Pick up if you're there.
我在比高大道的黑科技酒吧  我很害怕
I'm at this place on Pico Boulevard called Tech Noir. I'm really scared.
有人跟蹤我
I think that there's somebody after me.
我希望你快點聽這個口信
I hope that you play this back soon.
我想讓你和馬特儘快來接我
I need you and Matt to come and pick me up as soon as possible.
警方不停轉駁我的電話線  我會再試的
The police keep transferring me. I'm gonna give 'em another try.
這裡的號碼是5559175  快回電  我要你幫忙
The number here is 5559175. Call me, kiddo. I need your help.
薩拉·康納
是她
It's her.
-薩拉·康納? 我是戴探長  -聽著...
-Sarah Connor? It's Lieutenant Traxler.  -Listen...
別要我等或者轉線
Don't put me on hold. Don't transfer me to another department.
-我不會  -你在哪?
-I won't.  -Can you tell me where you are?
-一間叫黑科技的酒吧  -我知道 在比高大道
-I'm in this bar called Tech Noir. -I know it. It's on Pico.
-你沒事吧?  -沒事  但我不想離開
-Are you all right? -Yeah, but I don't wanna leave.
-我覺得有人在跟蹤我  -留心聽著
-I think there's a guy following me.  -Now, listen carefully.
你身處公眾地方  會較安全的
You're in a public place so you'll be safe.
留在顯眼處  別出去  別上廁所
Stay visible. Don't go outside.
-我會很快派車來  -好的
-I'll have a car there in a minute.  -OK.
那個傢伙沒有付錢
Hey, that guy didn't pay.
你想活著就跟我來
Come with me if you wanna live.
快點
Come on!
這是1-L19  有人襲擊後逃跑
This is one-L-19. I got a hit-and-run felony.
可疑車輛是舊型灰色福特 在第七街向西逃走
Suspect vehicle -Iate model grey Ford headed westbound on Seven.
他開得很快
He's really moving -punching lights.
馬上派救護車 來第七街和百老匯街交界
I'm gonna need an ambulance at Seventh and Broadway right now.
別動
Hold it.
Hold on.
你有沒有受傷?  你有沒有中槍?
Are you injured? Are you shot?
照我的說話做  照著做
Do exactly what I say. Exactly.
沒我允許不准動  不准發出聲音
Don't move unless I say. Don't make a sound unless I say.
明白嗎?
Do you understand?
-明白嗎?  -明白  求你別傷害我
-Do you understand?  -Yes. Please don't hurt me.
我是來幫你的
I'm here to help you.
我姓李斯 科技步隊中士DN38416 受命來保護你
I'm Reese. Sergeant Tech-Com. DN38416. Assigned to protect you.
你是被毀滅的目標
You've been targeted for termination.
嫌犯在國民街與奧運道交界 1-L19 請通話
Attempt to intercept, 1-L19.
這是1-L19  在奧運道向西行 接近奧佛蘭道
This is one-L19. Westbound on Olympic. Approaching Overland.
一定是搞錯了  我沒做過什麼
This is a mistake. I didn't do anything.
不  你會做的  你活著很重要
No, but you will. It's very important that you live.
不可能  那個人怎能站起來追你...
This isn't true. How could that man just get up after you...
它不是人  是機器
It's not a man. A machine.
一個魔鬼終結者  電腦達因系統101型號
A Terminator. Cyberdyne Systems model 101 .
機器?  像機械人?
A machine? Like a robot?
不是機械人  是電子人  電腦控制的生物
Not a robot. A cyborg-cybernetic organism.
-不  他剛才在流血  -等一下
-No. He was bleeding.  -Just a second.
伏下
Get your head down.
魔鬼終結者是個混合體
Listen. The Terminator's an infiltration unit. .
半人半機械
Part man, part machine
內裡是一個超合金的戰鬥骨架
Underneath it's a hyper-alloy combat chassis.
由微型處理器操作
Microprocessor controlled.
全副武裝  非常強勁  但外表是活人組織
Fully armoured, very tough. Outside it's living human tissue.
肌肉 皮膚 毛髮 血液 都是為電子人培植的
Flesh, skin, hair, blood  grown for the cyborgs.
-你想我怎樣做?  -留心聽著
-Look, Reese, I don't know  -Pay attention.
我要棄掉這輛車
I gotta ditch this car.
600系列有塑膠皮膚  很容易認得出
The 600-Series had rubber skin. We spotted them easy.
但這批是新造的  它們很像人類
But these are new. They look human.
流汗  口臭  諸如此類 很難辨認
Sweat, bad breath, everything. Very hard to spot.
我要等他向你下手  才能對付他
I had to wait till he moved on you before I could zero him.
聽著 我不是蠢才 他們還不能製造那樣的東西
Look, I am not stupid. They cannot make things like that yet.
還不可以  40年後就可以了
Not yet. Not for about forty years.
你是說它來自未來?
Are you saying it's from the future?
一個有可能的未來  從你的角度看
One possible future...from your point of view.
我對科技一竅不通
I don't know tech stuff.
那麼你也是來自未來?
Then you're from the future, too. Is that right?
-對  -對
-Right. -Right.
電子人感覺不到痛楚  可我能  別再那樣做
Cyborgs don't feel pain. I do. Don't do that again.
-放我走  -聽著...還有搞清楚點
-Just let me go.  -Listen and understand.
那個毀滅者就在外面
That Terminator is out there.
它不講情面  也不講道理
It can't be bargained with, it can't be reasoned with.
它不會同情或後悔...或者恐懼
It doesn't feel pity or remorse or fear
它絕不會甘休  永遠不會  直到你死掉
and it absolutely will not stop, ever, until you are dead.
你可否制止它?
Can you stop it?
我不知道
I don't know.
靠這些武器  我不知道
With these weapons, I don't know.
所有單位
All units.
在一個停車場裡發現可疑車輛
Ford suspect vehicle has been found in a parking structure
地點是第四街和百老匯街交界
at Fourth and Beaudry.
李斯?  為何是我?
Reese, why me?
它為何要對付我?
Why does it want me?
曾經發生了一場核戰
There was a nuclear war.
未來數年後
A few years from now,
這裡的一切...這個地方  所有的東西
all this, this whole place, everything,
都會消失  就此消失
it's gone, just gone.
有一些生還者
There were survivors.
零星...散落各地
Here, there.
沒有人知道是誰發動戰爭
Nobody even knew who started it.
-是那些機器  -我不明白
-It was the machines, Sarah.  -I don't understand.
防衛網路電腦
Defence network computers.
新型的  功能強勁
New, powerful,
接駁到所有東西  被委託操控一切重任
hooked into everything, trusted to run it all.
他們說它變得聰明起來  一種智慧的新秩序
They say it got smart, a new order of intelligence.
它視所有人類為威脅
Then it saw all people as a threat.
不能與我們共存
Not just the ones on the other side.
它在刹那間決定了我們的命運
It decided our fate in a microsecond.
滅絕
Extermination.
你可有目睹這場戰爭?
Did you see this war?
沒有  我在戰後長大  在廢墟中成長
No. I grew up after. In the ruins.
挨饑抵餓  躲避那些HK
Starving. Hiding from the H-Ks.
-HK?  -追捕殺手
-H-Ks?  -Hunter killers.
機械工廠製造的巡邏機器
Patrol machines built in automated factories.
我們大部分人被圍捕  關在營裡等候被消滅
Most of us were rounded up. Put in camps for orderly disposal.
這是被鐳射素描器烙下的
This was burned in by laser scanner.
我們有部分人得以活下來  去幹活
Some of us were kept alive. To work.
搬運屍體
Loading bodies.
那些消滅單位日以繼夜的運作
The disposal units ran night and day.
我們差點就喪命
We were that close to going out for ever.
但有一個人...教我們反抗
But there was one man who taught us to fight.
衝擊監禁營的線路
To storm the wire of the camps.
把那些金屬混蛋撞個稀巴爛
To smash those metal mother fuckers into junk.
他扭轉了局勢  帶我們脫離險境
He turned it around. He brought us back from the brink.
他姓康納  約翰·康納
His name was Connor. John Connor.
你的兒子  你未出世的兒子
Your son, Sarah. Your unborn son.
你來開車
Drive.
李斯
Reese!
不  李斯  不不  他們會殺死你的
No, Reese. No, no, no. They'll kill you.
在卡迪拉克房車裡的人  立刻舉高雙手
You in the Cadillac, let me see your hands now.
下車
Get out of the car.
跪下
Drop to your knees.
-下車  -跪下
-Out of the car.  -Drop to the ground.
薩拉...喝一點吧
Sarah. Sarah, try to drink some of this.
你肯定是他們?
Listen, are you sure it's them?
我應該看看屍體的
I mean, maybe I should look at the bodies.
已經證實了他們的身分  沒錯的
No. They've been identified and there's no doubt.
金珍  小夥子
Ginger. Kiddo.
-薩拉  這是索博曼醫生  -你好  薩拉
-Sarah, this is Dr Silberman.  -Hi, Sarah.
告訴他李斯對你說的一切  你應付得來嗎
Tell him everything Reese told you, Sarah. Do you feel up to that?
可以吧
Yeah, I guess so.
-你是個醫生?  -犯罪學心理醫生
-You're a doctor?  -Criminal psychologist.
-李斯是不是瘋的?  -這就是我們要查證的
-Is Reese crazy?  -That's what we're gonna find out.
你是個軍人吧  保衛著誰?
So you're a soldier. Fighting for whom?
隸屬貝裡率領的第132團  從21年到27年
With the 132nd under Perry. From '21 to '27.
那是...2027年?
That's the year 2027?
對  後來我被派到...
That's right. Then I was assigned...
-很好  -當約翰·康納的部下
-This is fucking great.  -under John Connor.
-敵人是誰?  -一個電腦防衛系統...
-Who was the enemy?  -A computer defence system...
該死  對不起
Goddamn! Sorry.
電腦動力系統替薩諾力製造的
built for SAC-NORAD by Cyberdyne Systems.
是吧
I see.
這個電腦認為
And this computer thinks .
殺了敵人的母親  就能勝利
it can win by killing the mother of its enemy
把他在孕育前就殺掉
Killing him, in effect, before he's even conceived.
算是倒逆的墮胎?
A sort of retroactive abortion?
索博曼笑死我了  那傢伙把他弄得一頭霧水
Silberman cracks me up. Last week, a guy burned his Afghan.
-他先弄得一團糟  -閉嘴
-He screwed it first...  -Ed, shut up.
那麼為何它...不殺死康納約翰?
Why didn't the computer just kill Connor then?
為何要有這個毀滅者的計畫?
Why this elaborate scheme with the Terminator?
我沒有選擇  它們的防禦網路被催毀
It had no choice. Their defence grid was smashed.
我們贏了  殺掉康納約翰也不會有何分別
We'd won. Taking out Connor then would make no difference.
天網要剷除他整個組織
Skynet had to wipe out his entire existence.
是不是當你們操控實驗室 找到...
Is that when you captured the lab complex and found...
那個什麼?
What is it called?
時空轉移裝置?
The time displacement equipment?
不錯  那個毀滅者已經穿越過來了
That's right. The Terminator had already gone through.
康納派我來攔截  它們炸毀了整個地方
Connor sent me to intercept and they blew the whole place.
那你怎麼回去?
Well, how are you supposed to get back?
我回不去了
I can't.
沒人能回家  也沒人能過來
Nobody goes home. Nobody else comes through.
只有他...和我
It's just him and me.
為何你沒帶武器?  一些更先進的武器?
Why didn't you bring any weapons? Something more advanced.
你們沒有鐳射槍的嗎?
Don't you have ray guns?
-鐳射槍  -給我看看一件未來的科技
-Ray guns.  -Show me a piece of future technology.
你要光著身體
You go naked. .
它跟由生物產生的磁場有關
Something about the field generated by a living organism
死物是不行的  那鬼東西不是我製造的
Nothing dead will go. I didn't build the fucking thing.
好的...但這個電子人  若它是金屬的...
OK, OK. But this cyborg, if it's metal...?
-被活組織包著的  -對  是的
-Surrounded by living tissue.  -Oh, right.
好東西  我能因他功成名就
This is great stuff. I could make a career out of this guy.
看這個多聰明?  不需要證據
You see how clever this part is? It doesn't require a shred of proof.
大部分妄想狂都很複雜  但這個卻很精明
Most paranoid delusions are intricate, but this is brilliant.
-為何另外兩女會被殺  -大部分記錄都在戰爭中遺失
-Why were the other women killed?  -Records were lost in the war.
天網對康納的母親幾乎一無所知
Skynet knew almost nothing about Connor's mother.
不知道她的全名和地址  只知道在哪個城市
Her full name, where she lived. They just knew the city.
那個毀滅者只是受系統操控
The Terminator was just being systematic.
-我們再談談...  -你聽得夠多了
-Let's go back...  -Look, you have heard enough.
我已經回答了你的問題  現在我要見薩拉
I have answered your questions. I have to see Sarah Connor.
-我作不了主  -那為何我要跟你談?
-I'm afraid that's not up to me.  -Then why am I talking to you?
-誰是主管?  -求你...
-Who is in authority here?  -Please...
閉嘴
Shut up!
你還是不明白  對不對?
You still don't get it, do you?
他會找到她  這就是他要做的  他只會這樣做
He'll find her. That's what he does. That's all he does.
你阻止不了他
You can't stop him.
他會掐住她喉嚨 挖出她心臟
He'll reach down her throat and pull her fucking heart out!
-醫生  -放開我
-Doc.  -Let go of me!
對不起
Sorry.
他是瘋子?
He's crazy?
用技術性的用語...他是個傻子
In technical terminology, he's a loon.
這是他們所謂的盔甲  我們的特種步隊都穿著這個
Sarah, this is what they call body armour. Our TAC guys wear these.
擋到12口徑的火力
It'll stop a 12-gauge round.
那個人一定是穿了它  觸摸一下吧
This other man must've been wearing one under his coat. Feel that.
-打碎擋風玻璃又怎麼說?  -他可能服了麻醉藥
-What about he punched through the windshield. -He was probably on PCP.
就算斷了骨頭  他也感覺不到
Broke every bone in his hand. He wouldn't feel it.
-這個傢伙...看見疤痕嗎?  -拿著
-There was this guy once...You see this scar?  -Here.
謝謝
Thank you.
這裡有一張沙發  躺下睡會吧
There's a couch in this other room. Stretch out and get some sleep.
你媽至少要一小時後  才能到這
Be at least an hour before your mother gets here.
-我睡不著  -試試吧
-I can't sleep.  -Try.
那張沙發其貌不揚  但很舒服的
It may not look it, but that couch is very comfortable.
你會絕對安全的  這座大廈裡有30個警員
You'll be perfectly safe. We got 30 cops in this building.
謝謝你
Thank you.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night.  -Good night.
我是薩拉·康納的朋友
I'm a friend of Sarah Connor.
聽說她在這  我能見她嗎
I was told she's here. Could I see her?
不能  你不能見她 她在錄口供
No. Can't see her. She's making a statement.
她在哪裡?
Where is she?
要一會的
It make take a while.
你想等的話  那邊有張長椅
If you wanna wait, there's a bench over there.
我會回來
I'll be back.
怎麼回事?
What the hell was that?
有槍聲
Gunshot!
-是不是恐怖分子?  -快走
-What is it, terrorists?  -Let's go
別走開
Stay here.
-我們快離開這裡 -來吧
-Let's get out of here! -Come on!
快點...
Move it, move it!
我看到他
I got him
看著他
Watch him.
-自動式武器 -快點  走吧
- Automatic weapons!  -Lock and load! Let's go!
著火了...
Fire! Fire!
艾特
Ed
薩拉
Sarah!
李斯
Reese.
這邊
This way.
現在是KFLB新聞時間 頻道4.36
KFLB news time. 4.36.
主要新聞 加州歷來最大型的
Top story, the largest single law enforcement mobilisation
執法行動正在展開
in California history is currently underway.
五個南部縣區正在大舉搜捕...
Police in five counties are engaged in a massive manhunt for...
拿著
Take this.
我們把這個推離公路
All right. Let's get this off the road.
-你冷嗎?  -凍僵了
-You cold?  -Freezing.
李斯?
Reese?
-你有名字嗎?  -凱爾
-You got a first name?  -Kyle.
凱爾  你穿越時空時是怎樣的?
Kyle, what's it like when you go through time?
白光
White light.
痛楚
Pain.
-或許就像出生時一樣吧  -我的天
-It's like being born maybe.  -My God.
我剛才吃了一記
I caught one back there.
-你中槍了?  -不是很嚴重
-You mean you got shot?  -It's not bad.
-我們要找醫生  -沒事的  算了吧
-We gotta get you to a doctor.  -It's OK. Forget it.
算了?  你瘋的嗎?  脫下它
What do you mean, forget it? Are you crazy? Take this off.
天
Jesus.
它穿過了皮肉
See? It passed right through the meat.
這會使我作嘔
This is gonna make me puke.
-你跟我談話好嗎?  -談什麼?
-Would you just talk about something?  -What?
不知道  隨便說吧  談談我的兒子
I don't know. Anything. Just talk. Tell me about my son.
他有我這麼高大
He's about my height.
他有你的眼睛
He has your eyes.
他是怎樣的?
What's he like?
你信任他  他有一種力量
You trust him. He's got a strength.
我願意為約翰·康納犧牲
I'd die for John Connor.
我現在至少知道給他取什麼名字
Well, at least now I know what to name him.
你不知道他父親是誰吧
Don't suppose you know who the father is
好讓我遇上他時不會叫他滾開
so I won't tell him to get lost?
約翰從來沒有提起他
John never said much about him.
-我知道他在戰前死了  -等一會
-I know he dies before the war...  -Wait.
我不想知道
I don't wanna know.
是不是約翰派你來的?
So was it John that sent you here?
是我自願的
I volunteered.
-為什麼?  -有機會認識傳奇人物
-Why?  -It was a chance to meet the legend.
薩拉·康納  教她兒子去抵抗...組織
Sarah Connor, who taught her son to fight, organise,
準備  從他小時就這樣教導他
prepare from when he was a kid.
當其他人還在戰前躲避時
When you were in hiding before the war.
你用過去式說一些 我還沒做的事
You're talking about things I haven't done yet in the past tense.
真的令我發瘋
It's driving me crazy.
你肯定沒找錯人?
Are you sure you have the right person?
肯定
I'm sure.
不是吧  我像未來的母親?
Come on! Do I look like the mother of the future?
我堅強又有組織能力嗎?  我連平衡收支都不會
I mean, am I tough? Organised? I can't even balance my checkbook.
我沒有要求這個榮譽  也不想要它
Look, Reese, I didn't ask for this honour and I don't want it.
絕對不要
Any of it.
你兒子有個口信給你  他要我背熟它
Your son gave me a message to give to you. Made me memorise it.
"感謝你在黑暗年代的勇氣"
Thank you, Sarah, for your courage through the dark years.
"你要面對的事我幫不到你  未來還未定案"
I can't help you with what you must soon face. The future is not set.
"你一定要比你想像中更堅強"
You must be stronger than you imagine you can be.
"你一定要活下去  否則我永不會存在"
You must survive or I will never exist.
就是這樣
That's all.
包紮得很好
It's a good field dressing.
你喜歡嗎?
You like it?
這是我的第一次
It's my first.
睡一會吧  快天亮了
Get some sleep. It'll be light soon.
好的
OK.
再跟我談一會
Talk to me some more.
談什麼?
About what?
告訴我你從哪裡來
Tell me about where you're from.
好的
All right.
你白天躲起來  但晚上你可以到處活動
You stay down by day, but at night you can move around.
你仍然要小心  因為HK會用紅外線
You still have to be careful because the H-Ks use infrared.
但它們還不夠聰明  約翰教了對付它們的方法
But they're not too bright. John taught us ways to dust them.
就是當那些滲透者出現的時候
That's when the infiltrators started to appear.
毀滅者是最新型的...最難對付的
The Terminators were the newest. The worst.
它正在以搜尋模式闖進你的防區
Traversing your sector in search mode.
在你以北750米的位置
750 metres north ofyour position.
我們走吧
Let's go.
-李斯  DN384...  -對  讓他進來
-Reese. DN384...  -Right. Let him in.
我們的監察者有一隻爪壞了 所以要減少巡邏
We're cutting short the patrol. Over
收到  揚基17  你可以安全折返
Roger, Yankee-1-7.You are clear to return.
毀滅者...
Terminator!
我夢見一些狗
I was dreaming about dogs.
我們用它們來發現毀滅者
We use 'em to spot Terminators.
你的世界很可怕
Your world is pretty terrifying.
老友  你裡面有只死貓嗎?
Hey, buddy, you got a dead cat in there or what?
可能的回應: 是  不是或走開
去你的  混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
媽媽的小屋 大熊鎮雲杉路181號
該死
God damn.
謝謝
Thank you.
迪基旅館
這個夠不夠?
Is this enough?
夠了  我不想問你從哪得來的
Yeah, it's enough. I don't wanna ask where you got it.
-來了  -我們要一個房間
-I'm coming.  -We need a room.
-好的  -要有廚房
-Ok.  -With a kitchen.
有沒有廚房的?
Do you have one with a kitchen?
我很想洗澡
I am dying for a shower.
還要檢查你的繃帶
We should check your bandage, too.
稍後吧  我要出去買東西
Later. I'm going out for supplies.
拿著這個
Keep this.
媽  我不能告訴你我在哪  有人叫我別說
No, I can't tell you where I am, Mom. I was told not to say.
我要知道在哪能找到你
I need to know where to reach you.
你叫我躲在小屋裡
You tell me to hide out at the cabin
但你卻不告訴我怎麼回事
and you won't tell me what's going on?
我真是擔心死了
I am worried sick here.
好吧  這是電話號碼
OK. OK, here's the number.
-準備好了嗎  -嗯  說吧
-You ready?  -Yes. Go ahead.
是4085551439...九號房
It's 408 555 1439. Room nine.
-記下了嗎?  -記下了
-Got it?  -I've got it.
我要掛了  抱歉我現在不能多說
I gotta go. I'm sorry I can't tell you more right now.
媽  我愛你
I love you, Mom.
我也愛你
I love you, too, sweetheart.
-迪基旅館  -把地址給我
-Tiki Motel.  -Give me your address there.
買了什麼?
What have we got?
樟腦丸...粟米糖漿...阿摩尼亞
Mothballs...corn syrup...ammonia.
晚餐吃什麼?
What's for dinner?
-塑膠炸彈  -好極了
-Plastique.  -That sounds good.
這是什麼?
What is it?
硝酸甘油固定劑  這樣會固定一點
It's a nitroglycerin base. It's a bit more stable.
我小時候學會的
I learned to make it when I was a kid.
不要沾到引線上
Make sure there's none on the threads.
這樣
Like this.
把蓋扭上
Screw the end cap on.
輕輕的
Very gently.
你的童年一定過得很有趣
You must've had a fun childhood.
很好
That's good.
再多做六個  我會開始做信管
All right. Six more like that and I'll get started on the fuses.
他會找到我們  是不是?
He'll find us, won't he?
可能吧
Probably.
這件事永遠不會完結  對嗎?
It'll never be over, will it?
看看我  我在顫抖
Look at me. I'm shaking.
好一個傳奇人物  你一定很失望了
Some legend. You must be pretty disappointed.
不是  我沒有失望
No, I'm not.
凱爾  你那個時代的女人
Kyle, the women in your time,
她們是怎樣的?
what are they like?
是精銳的戰士
Good fighters.
我不是那個意思
That's not what I meant.
有沒有意中人?
Was there someone special?
意中人?
Someone...?
女孩子
A girl, you know.
沒有
No.
從來沒有
Never.
從來沒有?
Never?
我很難過  我真的很難過
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
這麼多痛苦
So much pain.
痛苦是可以抑制的  只要你不去想它
Pain can be controlled. You just disconnect it.
那麼你沒有感覺?
So you feel nothing?
約翰·康納曾經給我一張你的照片
John Connor gave me a picture of you once.
當時我不明白原因
I didn't know why at the time.
它很舊了  有點破爛  也褪色了
It was very old, torn, faded.
你當時很年輕  就像現在一樣  看來有點悲傷
You were young like you are now. You seemed just a little sad.
我時常猜想你當時在想什麼
I used to always wonder what you were thinking at that moment.
我謹記著每一條線
I memorised every line,
每一條曲線
every curve.
薩拉  我穿越了時空來找你
I came across time for you, Sarah.
我愛你  我一直愛著你
I love you. I always have.
我不該那樣說的
I shouldn't have said that.
想快點
Think fast.
交換位置
Trade places.
快點  開快點
Faster. Drive faster.
凱爾  我的天
Kyle. Oh, my God.
混蛋
你別走開
You stay here.
我們快離開
Let's get outta here.
下車
Get out.
凱爾  站起來
Kyle. Come on. Get up.
幫我
Help me.
來吧
Come on.
幫我  快走...
Help me. Get out. Get out.
走
Get out.
快點
Faster.
不要停  走
Don't stop. Run.
薩拉?
Sarah.
凱爾
Kyle.
凱爾  我們成功了  我們成功了
We did it, Kyle. We got him.
不
No.
等一會
Wait.
你幹什麼?
What are you doing?
掩護  令它追蹤不到我們
Cover, so he can't track us.
啟動自動序列
快點  來吧
Come on.
不  凱爾  來吧
No. Kyle. Come on.
-來吧  -別理會我
-Come on.  -Leave me here.
快走  李斯  站起來  士兵
Move it, Reese. On your feet, soldier.
站起來  快走
On your feet. Move it.
後面  去後面
Get back. Go back.
-薩拉  快逃  -不
-Run, Sarah.  -No.
快跑
Run.
來吧  混蛋
Come on, mother fucker.
不...
No.
啟動卸貨
混蛋  你被毀滅了
You're terminated, fucker.
凱爾
Kyle.
第7個錄音 11月10日
Tape 7, November 10th.
我說到哪裡?
Where was I?
最難決定的是該告訴你什麼和不告訴你什麼
What's difficult is trying to decide what to tell you and what not to.
我還有時間考慮
But I guess I have a while
在你長大到明白這些錄音之前
before you're old enough to understand these tapes
現在來說 這些錄音只是給我自己的  好讓我理清頭緒
They're more for me at this point just so that I can get it straight.
入滿它
Fill her up.
我是否該告訴你  關於你父親的事?
Should I tell you about your father?
孩子 那是個難題
Boy, that's a tough one.
會影響你派他來這的決定嗎
Will it effect your decision to send him here
知道他是你父親
knowing that he is your father?
如果你不派凱爾來  就不會有你
If you don't send Kyle, you can never be.
天  想著這件事會使人發瘋的
God, a person could go crazy thinking about this.
我相信我會告訴你的
I suppose I will tell you.
這是我至少該做的
I owe him that.
也許這有幫助的  如果...
Maybe it'll help if...
你知道這個 在我們共處的短暫的時光裡
you know that in the few hours that we had together,
我們愛了一生一世
we loved a lifetime's worth.
-他剛剛說什麼?  -他說  "小姐  你很漂亮"
-What did he just say?  -He says you're very beautiful.
他不敢問你拿五元的照相費
He is ashamed to ask you for five dollars for this picture.
但如果他不問你要  他父親就會打他
But if he doesn't, his father will beat him.
孩子  真會做生意
Pretty good hustle, kid.
他剛剛說什麼?
What did he just say?
他說 有一場風暴要來了
He said there's a storm coming in.
我知道
I know.
鳴謝赫倫·艾裡遜